This is a drawing of a normal modern
animal that you'd recognize, except they
drew it in a way that many early science
illustrators drew dinosaurs, with the
skin just wrapped around the bone
without muscle, turning this normal
animal into a monster. Can you guess
what it is?
That's a zebra. Okay, what about this
one? That's a baboon. This one's my
favorite. Can you guess this one? That's
a hippo. This practice is called shrink
wrapping, and it caused a lot of really
big misunderstandings about what
dinosaurs actually looked like. They
were way chunkier than people think.
Artists and scientists are correcting
that now. They're adding more loose skin
and muscles and fatty tissues. They're
showing dinosaurs like the animals they
really were. If you want to see what
dinosaurs really look like, watch our
longer video.